Guide to the New York State College of Human Ecology records, 1900-2017
Cornell University, New York State College of Human Ecology records,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State College of Human Ecology records, 1900-2017.
23-2-2817
New York State College of Human Ecology.
76.5 cubic feet.
Reports, committee minutes, correspondence, statistical data, audiocassettes, photographs, videocassettes, and subject files.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Reports, committee minutes, statistical data, correspondence, audiocassettes, photographs, videocassettes, subject files, and other records of the College of Human Ecology, particularly of the Office of the Dean and the Associate Deans.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The New York State College of Human Ecology was formerly the New York State College of Home Economics. Home Economics began as part of the Extension Service in 1900 with the arrival of Martha Van Rensselaer and the establishment of the Farmers' Wives Reading Course. In 1903-1904 Martha Van Rensselaer and Anna Botsford Comstock taught three courses within the College of Agriculture at Cornell University, relating to home and family life. In 1907 the Department of Home Economics was established at Cornell, with Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose as its first instructors. In 1911 the two women became the first full-time female faculty members at Cornell. The Department of Home Economics became a school in 1919 and in 1925, the first state chartered College of Home Economics in the country. In 1969 it was renamed the New York State College of Human Ecology.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Reports, committee minutes, correspondence, speeches, statistical data, audiotapes, photographs, videotapes, subject files, and other records of the Office of the Dean and the Associate Deans.
Also speeches, trip files, awards and other records of Deans Jerome M. Ziegler, Francille Firebaugh, Patsy Brannon, Lisa Staiano-Coico, and Associate Deans Charles McClintock and Jennifer Gerner. Includes Alumni Association photographs, minutes of the Committee on Academic Status, Educational Policy Committee Minutes, faculty meeting minutes, and Academic Planning and Budget Reports.
Includes college facility reports from various construction projects.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Human Ecology.; Brannon, Patsy M.; Firebaugh, Francille M., 1933-; Gerner, Jennifer L.; McClintock, Charles C., 1946-; Staiano-Coico, Lisa.; Ziegler, Jerome M.; Cornell University--Administration.; Cornell University--Faculty.; New York State College of Human Ecology.Educational Policy Committee.; New York State College of Human Ecology.Committee on Academic Status.
Form and Genre Terms:
Videotapes.; Audiotapes.; Photographs.; Slides (photographs).; Compact discs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
See also New York State College of Home Economics records, #23-2-749
See also New York State College of Human Ecology annual reports, #23-2-2523
Podcasts can be found online here: http://ecommons.cornell.edu/handle/1813/7963
Publications can be found online here: http://ecommons.cornell.edu/handle/1813/7926
Access Restrictions:
Restricted to permission of the office of origin, except for boxes 5, 8, 9, 22, 24, 29, 34, 43, 48, 53, 54, 66-68, 70, 72-74, 76, 86, 91, 104, 107-112, 115, 116, 119, 120, 124 and oversized folder.
Electronic faculty annual reports are restricted until 5 years after creation.
RELATED MATERIALS
The videos Valuing Our Past, Creating Our Future and Celebrating 25 Years as Human Ecology from this collection have been digitized and can be found on Cornell's Library Media Space website along with other Home Economics and related films.
See also New York State College of Home Economics records #23-2-749, http://resolver.library.cornell.edu/cgi-bin/EADresolver?id=RM00749.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Associate Dean's Files
A. Reports
Box 1- Folders: 1-13, 42, 44; Box 64- Folder: 3
B. College Committees, Policies, Programs
Box 1- Folders: 14-26, 29-31, 40-41, 43, 45-46; Box 23- Folders: 59-60; Box 35- Folders: 1-5; Box 64- Folders: 4-5; Box 69- Folders: 1-17
C. Awards/ Fellowships/ Endowments
Box 23- Folders: 1-58; Box 35- Folders: 9-12; Box 49- Folders: 1-10, 16-25, 29-35; Box 69- Folders: 18-35.
D. Instruction
Box 1- Folders: 27-28; Box 35- Folders: 6-8; Box 49- Folders: 11-15, 26-28, 36-37
E. Chairs and Deans Meetings
Box 1- Folders: 32-39
Series II. Dean's Files
A. Jerome Ziegler
Boxes 2, 3, 4,
B. Francille Firebaugh
1)Awards
Box 43
2)Speeches and Trip Reports
a)Combined Speeches and Trip Reports
Box 12
b)Trip Reports
Boxes 30, 31, 32, 61
c)Speeches
Box 42
3)Subject Files and Correspondence
Boxes 10, 11, 13-21, 25-28, 36-41 (except folders 1-19 of Box 41), 44-46 (except folders 1-16, 35-37 of Box 45), 50-52, 55-60
4)Chairs and Deans Meetings
Boxes 40, 44, 51, 59, 62
C. Patsy Brannon
1. Policies, Committees, etc.
Boxes 62, 71, 75,101
2. Trip Files
Boxes 59, 80, 81, 85
3. Accounting Files
Box 59, Box 93 (folders 22-31)
4. Correspondence
Box 77, Box 93 (folders 1-12)
5. Subject Files
Boxes 63, 77-80, 82 (folders 1-14), 83 (folders 1-17), 84, 93(folders 13-28), 95(folders 1-23), 97(folders 1-29), 98(folders 1-15 and 17-19), 100(folders 1-16), 101(folders 7,8,20,21)
6. Cornell Migrant Program
Box 82 (folder 11-26)
7. Speeches
Box 83 (folders 18-31), Box 101 (folders 16,20,21)
8. Workforce Planning
Box 106
9. Chairs and Deans Meetings
Boxes 75, 82
D. Lisa Staiano-Coico
1. Accounting Files
Box 94
2. Correspondence
Box 92
3. Subject Files
Boxes 87, 92(folders 1-15,23-30),94(folders 23-30),96(folders 1-20),99(folders 1,2,4-6,10-18),101(folders 1-4)
4. Branding
Box 92 (folders 16-22)
5. Speeches
Box 94 (folders 1-9)
6. Chairs and Deans Meetings
Box 94(folder 14 -22)
E. Alan Mathios
1. Subject Files
Box 87, 123, 125-128
2. Chairs and Deans Meetings
Box 128
3. Memoranda of Understanding
Box 128
4. Speeches
Box 127
Series III. Committee Files (Refer to the deans' files above for additional material.)
A. Academic Status
Box 7 (files 36-44)
B. Educational Policy
Boxes 6, 7 (files 1-35), 33
C. Faculty Meetings
Boxes 8, 9, 48, 53
D. Standing Committee
Box 47 & 64 (folders 1-2)
E. Affirmative Action
Box 65
F. College Organization and College Study Committees
Box 106
G. Academic Planning and Budgeting
Box 41 (folders 1-19), 45 (folders 1-16, 35-37), 87
H. Communications Working Group
Box 106
I. External Relations Committee
Box 106
J. Morale
Box 106
K. Quality Improvement Process (QIP)
Box 106
L. Undergraduate Education
Box 106
M. Diversity
Boxes 75, 117
Series IV. Faculty Biographical Files
Boxes 22, 24, 54, 74, 104
Series V. Faculty Annual Reports
Boxes 22, 24, 54, 74, 104
Series VI. Student Guides, Directories, Organizational Charts, Programs
Box 29
Series VII. Photographs/Slides
Boxes 5, 34, 66, 67, 68, 86, 128
Series VIII. Cassette Tapes, CDs and DVDs
tr 7860a-tr 7864a, tr 7992a-tr 7994a
Series IX. Videos
V-498-504, V-562-578, V-585-587, V-646-647, V-792-794
Series X. Publications and Reports
Boxes 70, 103
Series XI. Facility Records
Boxes 70, 106, 118, 121, 122
Series XII. Memorabilia
Box 72, 73, 76, 133
Series XIII. Conferences, Symposiums, Institutes
Boxes 70, 88
Series XIV. Curriculum/Theses Titles
Box 91
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Associate Dean's Files
  - A. Reports
    - Reports - Quality of Undergraduate Education (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Reports - College Study on Undergraduate Education, 1983-06 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - President's Committee to Study the College of Home Economics (a.k.a. The Blackwell Report), 1966-12 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Reports - Annual: Institutional Studies, 1979-1982, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Reports - Annual: International Programs, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Reports - Annual: Special Educational Projects, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Reports - Annual: College Research and Graduate Education, 1973-1974,1975-1976,1977-1978,1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Reports - Annual: College Grants Committee, 1980-1981,1982-1985, 1986-1987, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Reports - Annual: Academic Integrity Hearing Board, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Reports - Annual: Committee on Academic Status, 1974-1975, 1976-1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Reports - Annual: Admissions Committee, 1978-1979, 1980-1985, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Reports - Annual: Educational Policies Committee, 1980-1983 and index, 1983-1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Reports - Annual: Field Study Committee, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - College Research Reports-Printed, 1979-1980, 1981-1982, 1983, 1985, 1986, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Reports- Annual: Nominations Committee, 1972-1993 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Faculty Effort Reports, 1989-1995 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Faculty Effort Reports, 1995-2000 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Faculty Effort Reports, 2000-2004 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Annual Reports for Academic Programs, 1990-1992 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - College Reports, 1992-1997 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Statistical Data Reports, 1997-2005 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Statistical Data Reports, 2006-6007 (Box 88, Folder 6A)
  - B. College Committees, Policies, Programs
    - Human Ecology/ University Relations, 1986, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Human Ecology Faculty Council, 1974-1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Educational Policies Committee/ Undergraduate Teaching Assistants, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Human Ecology Admissions Policies (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Educational Policies Committee - Report of International Education, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Educational Policies Committee - Index to Minutes (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Human Ecology Symposium, 1979-11 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Human Ecology Registered Programs (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Undergraduate Recruitment Marketing Strategies (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - President's Fund for Educational Initiatives/ Report on Human Ecology Programs, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Human Ecology Undergraduate Study Abroad, 1981-1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Undergraduate Education Statistical Data, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Corporate Relations (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - College 65th Anniversary, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - College Calendar, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Human Ecology Days, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Research Advisory Committee, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Evening of Excellence - Programs (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Human Ecology Standing Committees, 1950 - present (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Persons Nominated for Voting Membership in the College (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Human Ecology Faculty Organization and Administration (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - M.P.S.- Masters of Professional Studies, 1989-1991 (Box 23, Folder 59)
    - M.P.S.- Masters of Professional Studies, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 60)
    - Events- Family Weekend, 1991-1993 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Exhibits- Student Leaders, 1990-1993 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Exhibits- Teaching Excellence, 1985-1993 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Persons Nominated for Voting Membership in the College (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Human Ecology Faculty Organization and Administration, 1960-1989 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Instruction- Family and Consumer Science Teacher Education, 1998-1999 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Program- Cortland Teacher Certification, 1995-1997 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Program- Wells Home Economics Certification, 1991-1992 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Program- Cortland Teacher Certification- Memorandum of Agreement, 1996 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Program- Albany Internship, 1997 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Program- Gerontology, 1991-1999 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Program- Swedish Childcare Field Internship-Mon Cochran, 1996 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Program- Elementary Education Training Certification Agreement with Wells College, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Program- Social Worker Correspondence, 1996-2000 (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Program- Social Worker Reaccreditation- Correspondence, 1995-1998 (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - Program- Research and Extension Programs, 1997 (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - Reports- Human Development- Mission Statement, Name Change, Report on the Undergraduate Program, 1994-1999 (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - Admissions Statistics (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - Admissions- Reorganization, 1997 (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - Human Biology, Health and Society- Establishment, 1998-2001 (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - Technology Group Creation, 1996-1998 (Box 69, Folder 16)
    - TV Center- Media and Technology Services, 1999 (Box 69, Folder 17)
    - New Faculty Orientation Material, 1979-1988 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - New Faculty Orientation Material, 1989-1995 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Computing at Human Ecology, 1987-1991 (Box 88, Folder 9)
  - C. Awards/ Fellowships/ Endowments
    - Menyhart Memorial Scholarship (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Powell Fellowship-Correspondence, 1962-1970 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Margaret Brew Scholarship and Powell Endowment, 1960-1969 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Margaret Brew Scholarship and Powell Endowment, 1960-1969 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Margaret Brew Scholarship and Powell Endowment, 1960-1969 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Margaret Brew Scholarship and Powell Endowment, 1960-1969 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - General Foods Fellowships, 1956-1957 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - General Foods Fellowships, 1958-1959 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - General Foods Fellowships, 1960-1961 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - General Foods Fellowships, 1962-1964 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - General Foods Fellowships, 1965-1971 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - General Foods Fellowships, 1980-1989 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - College Fellowships, 1982-1985 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - College Fellowships, 1985-1987 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - College Fellowships, 1987-1989 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - College Fellowships, 1989-1990 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - College Fellowships, 1990-1991 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - College Fellowships, 1991-1992 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - College Fellowships, 1992-1993 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Gifft/Smith Fellowship, 1984-1985 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - SUNY Graduate Fellowship- Regina Cannon, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - SUNY Chancellor's Award- Cindy Hazen, 1990-1991 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - SUNY Chancellor's Award- Ruth Constantine, 1990-1991 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - SUNY Chancellor's Award- Peter Zorn, 1991-1992 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - SUNY Graduate Fellowships, 1992-1993 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - SUNY Graduate Fellowships, 1992-1993 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - SUNY Chancellor's Award-David Levitsky, 1992-1993 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - SUNY Chancellor's Award-Jennifer Greene, 1993-1994 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - SUNY Empire State Honors Scholarships- Minorities, 1989-1990 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - SUNY Empire State Honors Scholarships- Minorities, 1990-1993 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Ruthanna Wood Davis Award in Division of Nutritional Sciences- Description of Award, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 53)
    - Robert Cherry Award/ Great Teacher- Urie Bronfenbrenner, 1990 (Box 105, Folder 30)
    - Honoring Faculty Excellence Promotion to Professor, 1988-1993 (Box 23, Folder 30A)
    - Evening of Excellence, 1989-1990, 1990-1991 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Evening of Excellence, 1991-1992 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Evening of Excellence, 1992-1993 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Council for Advancement and Support of Education (CASE) Awards, 1987-1997 (Box 105, Folder 37)
    - International Travel Award-Andrea Anderson, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - International Travel Award-Karen Edward and Mumtaz Award, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - International travel Award-Pamela Ferry and Luis Juan Ramos, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - International Travel Award-Veni Hadju, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - International Travel Award-Laurine Thomas and Syed Kalamuddin, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - International Travel Award-Ann Coghlan, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - International Travel Award-Sheila Humiston, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - International Travel Award-Dong Yean Park, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 44)
    - International Travel Award-Denise Boudreau, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 45)
    - International Travel Award-Sharon Brisolara, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 46)
    - International Travel Award-Claire Foley, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 47)
    - International Travel Award- Yookyung Kwon, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 48)
    - International Travel Award-Michelle Liechtman, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 49)
    - International Travel Award-Zelmire Nunez Del Prado, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 50)
    - International Travel award-Dandan Pan, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 51)
    - Merrill Presidential Scholars, 1992-1993 (Box 23, Folder 52)
    - Merrill Presidential Scholars, 1992-1993 (Box 23, Folder 53)
    - National Hispanic Scholarship, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 54)
    - Upperclass Summer Scholarship, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 57)
    - Distinguished Teachers Award, 1991-1993 (Box 23, Folder 58)
    - Students- Graduate Fellowships, 1993-1994 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Students-Undergraduates-Financial Aid/Scholarships, 1993-1994 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - SUNY Fellowships, 1993-1994 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Faculty Awards-Faculty Exchange Scholar, 1990 (Box 105, Folder 38)
    - Faculty Awards-Faculty Scholars Program, 1992 (Box 105, Folder 39)
    - Faculty Awards-SUNY Chancellors-Virginia Utermohlen and Sheila Danko, 1997 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Faculty Awards-SUNY Chancellors-Steve Robertson and Alan Mathios, 1996 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Faculty Awards-SUNY Chancellors-Priscilla Tennant, 1995 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Staff Awards-SUNY Chancellors- Brenda Bricker, 1996 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Evening of Excellence (Honoring Undergraduates), 2000, 2003, 2004, 2006, 2007 (Box 49, Folder 4a)
    - Evening of Excellence (Honoring Undergraduates), 1997-1999 (Box 49, Folder 4b)
    - Evening of Excellence (Honoring Undergraduates), 1994-1995; 1995-1996; 1996-1997 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Evening of Excellence (Honoring Undergraduates), 1992-1993; 1993-1994 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Outstanding Seniors, 1991-1992, 1992-1993 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Outstanding Seniors-Exhibits, 1993-1994 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Outstanding Seniors- Photographs, 1994-1997 (Box 69, Folder 31)
    - Outstanding Seniors, 1994-1995 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Outstanding Seniors, 1995-1996 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Outstanding Seniors, 1997 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Outstanding Seniors, 1998 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Outstanding Seniors, 1999-2000 (Box 69, Folder 30)
    - Outstanding Seniors-Transcripts, 2000-2001 (Box 69, Folder 28)
    - Outstanding Seniors-Photographs, 2000-2001 (Box 69, Folder 29)
    - Outstanding Seniors, 2001, 2004-2007 (Box 105, Folder 51)
    - Undergraduates-Financial Aid Scholarships, 1997-1998 (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - Undergraduates-Financial Aid Scholarships, 1996-1997 (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - Undergraduates-Financial Aid Scholarships, 1995-1996 (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - Undergraduates-Financial Aid Scholarships, 1994-1995 (Box 49, Folder 19)
    - Undergraduate Honors Program, 1985 (Box 105, Folder 50)
    - Undergraduate Honors Program, 1998-1999 (Box 49, Folder 20)
    - Undergraduate Honors Program, 1997-1998 (Box 49, Folder 21)
    - Undergraduate Honors Program, 1996-1997 (Box 49, Folder 22)
    - Undergraduate Honors Program, 1995-1996 (Box 49, Folder 23)
    - Undergraduate Honors Program, 1994-1995 (Box 49, Folder 24)
    - Undergraduate Honors Program, 1994-1995 (Box 49, Folder 25)
    - Undergraduate Honors Program, 1992-1993 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Undergraduate Honors Program, 1993-1994 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Undergraduate Honors Program, 1991-1995 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Graduate Student Recognition, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Graduate Student Recognition, 1994 (Box 49, Folder 30)
    - Graduate Student Recognition, 1995 (Box 49, Folder 30A)
    - Graduate Student Recognition, 1996 (Box 49, Folder 29)
    - Graduate Fellowships, 1999-2007 (Box 49, Folder 30B)
    - Graduate Fellowships, 1998-1999 (Box 49, Folder 31)
    - Graduate Fellowships, 1997-1998 (Box 49, Folder 32)
    - Graduate Fellowships, 1996-1997 (Box 49, Folder 33)
    - Graduate Fellowships, 1995-1996 (Box 49, Folder 34)
    - Graduate Fellowships, 1994-1995 (Box 49, Folder 35)
    - SUNY Chancellor's Award-Christine Miller, 2001 (Box 69, Folder 18)
    - SUNY Chancellor's Award-Jeff Haugaard, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 19)
    - SUNY Chancellor's Award-Jim Garbarino, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 20)
    - SUNY Chancellor's Award-Sheila Danko, 1999 (Box 69, Folder 21)
    - SUNY Chancellor's Award-Rosemary Avery, 1998 (Box 69, Folder 22)
    - Student Leaders-Photographs, 1994-1995 (Box 69, Folder 23)
    - Student Leaders-Photographs, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 24)
    - Student Leaders-Photographs, 1999-2000 (Box 69, Folder 25)
    - Student Leaders-Experiential Transcripts, 1998-1999 (Box 69, Folder 26)
    - Student Leaders-Photographs, 1998-1999 (Box 69, Folder 27)
    - Undergraduate Research, 2001-2002 (Box 69, Folder 32)
    - Undergraduate Research, 2000-2001 (Box 69, Folder 33)
    - Undergraduate Research, 1999-2000 (Box 69, Folder 34)
    - Undergraduate Research Forms, 1994-1995 (Box 69, Folder 35)
    - Undergraduate Research, 1991-1992 (Box 23, Folder 55)
    - Undergraduate Research, 1992-1993 (Box 23, Folder 56)
    - List of Endowed Graduate Fellowships and Undergraduate Scholarships, 2004 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - D. Instruction
    - Teaching and Advising Sourcebook, 1976-1981, 1982-1987, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Faculty Handbooks, 1974, 1978, 1985, 1989, 1990, 1993, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Faculty Handbook, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 28A)
    - Instruction-Faculty-Teaching and Advising (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Instruction-Undergraduate Education-Summer Session, 1987-1993 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Instruction-Undergraduate Education Policies-15 Credit Requirement, 1979-1985 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Undergraduate Courses-HE 110 "Explorations in Human Ecology", 1996 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Undergraduate Courses-HE 110 "Explorations in Human Ecology", 1995 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Undergraduate Courses-HE 110 "Explorations in Human Ecology", 1994 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Undergraduate Courses-HE 110 "Explorations in Human Ecology"- evaluations, readings, 1994 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Undergraduate Courses-HE 110 "Explorations in Human Ecology"- evaluations, readings, 1994 (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - Undergraduate Research, 1995-1996 (Box 49, Folder 26)
    - Undergraduate Research, 1994-1995 (Box 49, Folder 27)
    - Experiential Learning (Box 49, Folder 28)
    - Graduate Degrees Awarded-MPS, 1980-1989, 1990-1999 (Box 49, Folder 36)
    - Grants/Support/Travel, 1993-1994 (Box 49, Folder 37)
    - Teaching Excellence Seminars, 1988 (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - Teaching Excellence Seminars, 1988 (Box 88, Folder 11)
    - Teaching Excellence Seminars, 1990-1991 (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - Teaching Excellence Seminars, 1991-1992 (Box 88, Folder 13)
    - Teaching Excellence Seminars, 1993-1994 (Box 88, Folder 14)
    - Ballots: faculty vote on academic matters, 1994-1999 (Box 88, Folder 15)
  - E. Chairs and Deans Meetings
    - Chairs and Deans Meetings, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Chairs and Deans Meetings, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Chairs and Deans Meetings, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Chairs and Deans Meetings, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Chairs and Deans Meetings, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Chairs and Deans Meetings, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Chairs and Deans Meetings, 1982, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Chairs and Deans Retreat, 1986-11-19 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Series II. Dean's Files
  - A. Jerome Ziegler (1978-1988)
    - Academic Advising Recommendations, 1974-10-03 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Recommendations
    - Academic Services, 1975-1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Counseling, Advising, Recruiting, Admission Policy, Learning Circles Project, Minority Students, Correspondence
    - Academic Services Review, 1978-06 (Box 2, Folder 3)